<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-12T23:49:41-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MOUNTAIN DU</title><subtitle>The mountains are calling and I must go.  - John Muir</subtitle><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><entry><title type="html">Lavaredo Ultra Trail 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/lavaredo.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lavaredo Ultra Trail 2017" /><published>2017-08-24T20:45:13-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-24T20:45:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/lavaredo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/lavaredo.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ultratrail.it/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Lavaredo Ultra Trail&lt;/a&gt; is a 120km ultra trail race with 5800m of elevation gain in the Dolomites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I logged less than 500 miles of running in 2017 before the race. I should have run a lot more often considering how mild this winter was in Toronto. A significant portion of the runs were done on the trails. It turns out that downtown Toronto has some very nice &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/987711599&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;single tracks&lt;/a&gt;. Given my training, I set my goal at 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Pre-Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to arrive at Venice on Thursday morning (Jun. 22nd), so I could spend a day getting some rest. But I missed the flight due to the long delay at LaGuardia on my way back from a conference. I had to rebook the flight next day, landingat Venice on Friday morning (Jun. 23rd). I then took the ATVO bus at the airport to Cortina and arrived at the nice little ski town at 1:30pm.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then had my gear checked and got my bib at the ice stadium. I spent most of the time dozing at the lobby of the hotel I would stay in after the race. I was still sleep deprived when the race starts at 11pm, but the exciting music and speech pumped my adrenaline up. So off we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/224698518&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Cortina (0km) - Cimabanche (66 km)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ran cross the town and soon started our first climb of 500m. The trail was crowded at first, and it was a bit frustrating at the descent, when I had to constantly slow down. Fatigue crept up on me just a couple of hours into the race, probably a result of my lack of training and lack of sleep. I decided to have a gel every 90 minutes, and that brought some strength to my legs. I did not linger in the first two aid stations,&amp;nbsp;Ospitale (18km) and&amp;nbsp;Federavecchia (33km). My rank moved up to 808 at Misurina (42km).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the lovely Lake Misurina, we started our 600m ascent towards&amp;nbsp;Forc. Lavaredo. I ran out of gels by then, and the lack of calorie made the last part of the climb to Refugio Auronzo quite tiresome. So when I finally arrived at the welcoming refugio, I decided to stay longer to eat as much as I can and get some rest. Half an hour later, I started off again, feeling great. After a short climb, I arrived at Forc. Laveredo. It was a highlight of the race, with a gorgeous panorama view of the Dolomites. I felt very good at the 1000m descent, and passed a good number of runners when I reached the bottom of the valley. After that it was another 5k of dirt road gently uphill. By then the sun was out and there was little shade. I tried to push the pace, but soon it was reduced to walking again. After a miserable hour, I reached the Cimabanche (66km).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_082511.jpg&quot; &gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Cimabanche (66km) - Cortina (120km)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Cimabanche, I got my drop bag. I had a set of clean clothes in the bag, but because of the heat, I decided to keep my singlets and shorts and &amp;nbsp;only change my socks. After a brief rest, I left the aid station for the climb up to Forc. Lerosa. I was breathing heavily on way up, but the heart rate remains under 130, and I couldn't pick up the pace either. I arrived at&amp;nbsp;Malga Ra Stua (76km) at 1:10pm. I took a 40 minute rest lying on the grass, trying to regain some energy for the next stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next section over Forc. Col dei Bos, is the toughest of the race, with over 1000m of elevation gain in 10 kilometers. From Malga Ra Stua, there's first a descent of 300m, and then we turned into valley Val Travenanzes and started the march to the pass. Half way into the valley and the sun was gone. A thunderstorm was developing. I always thought with all the hiking, I should be good at those long climbs. Well not really. People were passing me right and left. I gathered all my strength so that I would keep on walking, but that was all I could manage. At 4:47pm, I arrived at Malga&amp;nbsp;Travenanzes (89km), a short stop with water and some light refreshments. I must have looked terrible that the volunteers assumed that I was going to drop out, and told me that I could do so at the next check point. Despite all the struggle, dropping out never crossed my mind. I was mildly offended so I waved them off and got back on the trail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/north-face-lavaredo-ultra-trail-2017-3677855-47574-2106-node.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After what seemed like an eternity, I finally got to the top of Forc. Col dei Bos (91km), 2331m above sea level. By then it started drizzling and temperature dropped. Fortunately I was already heading down, and the rain was fairly mild. At 6:44pm, I arrived at Col Gallina (96km). After a brief rest, I started the 400m ascent to Refugio Averau. The rest of the race was a blur to me. I was exhausted and all I could manage was to put one foot in front of the other. &amp;nbsp;My pace was reduced to a pathetic 30min/mile. Nonetheless, I kept pushing and reached Refugio Averau (100km) at 8:33pm. It was mostly downhill for the next 4km. Another hour later, I arrived at Passo Giau (104km). From Passo Giau, there was a short but steep climb of about 200m. By then it was completely dark, so I had to be more careful of the footing. Looking up, there was a long line of runners with their bright headlamps. It meant that there was still a long way to the top. This was disheartening, particularly at this stage of the race. Even though it didn't rain much, the thunder and lightening was unsettling. My fellow runners seemed pretty chill though. It did help me speed up, as I was legitimately worried that I might get hit. I got to Mondeval (107km) at 11:02pm. There was one finally climb of 120m, before I finally reached the top of Forc. Ambrizzola at 2271m above sea level. Afterwards it's all downhill, all the way back to Cortina. I arrived at Refugio Croda da Lago (111km) at 11:45pm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was quite relieved when I got to the refugio. When I was sitting there taking a break, I suddenly lost all the motivations. I was talking to a fellow runner when I realized that I had to finish within 26 hours to qualify for Western States. So I would have little chance to qualify. As a result, I spent more time than I should have at the aid station. For some stupid reason, I also did not refill my water bottle. When I left the refugio, the rain was heavier, but the thunder and lightning died down as we were now below tree level. The trail was slippery from the rainfall. There were quite a few runners right in front me, so I had to be careful sliding down so that I would not crash into them. It was quite frustrating. After a while, I gave up and settled with walking pace. After an hour, I ran out of water, and even though I could see the town from time to time, the trail just didn't seem to end. I arrived at the final check point Lago D'Ajal(116km) at 1:16am. Shortly afterwards, we finally got to the end of the single track and were back on paved road. Physically and mentally, I was done by then. The last 3km took me 45 minutes. I barely gathered enough strength to jog the last 100 meters as I approached the finish line to put an end to the race. Officially, I finished after 27:02 hours at 2:02am on Sunday morning and ranked at 880 out of 1070 finishers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/
north-face-lavaredo-ultra-trail-2017-3677855-47569-6672-node.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Post Race Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning from my experience at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountain-du.com/2017/01/ttf/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ultra Trail Tai Mo Shan TTF&lt;/a&gt;, I did some specific training running downhills. So I was much more comfortable pushing the pace now during downhill. It also put less stress on my knees. The gels also helped a great deal in the first half. If I would force myself to take them the second half, I might have run faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major problem I had is the lack of volume in training. Had I run more leading to the race, I should be able to finish within 24 hours. Also I lost a lot of time going uphill. I pushed as hard as I could, but I was slow and heart rate was low. I think the problem was about the leg muscles. I need to hit the gym and do some leg workouts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strava:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/1064911012&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;https://www.strava.com/activities/1064911012&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170623_160412.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170623_160412&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170623_160412.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170623_160412&quot; title=&quot;20170623_160412&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170623_195523.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170623_195523&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170623_195523.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170623_195523&quot; title=&quot;20170623_195523&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_051914.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_051914&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_051914.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_051914&quot; title=&quot;20170624_051914&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_055321.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_055321&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_055321.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_055321&quot; title=&quot;20170624_055321&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_070956.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_070956&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_070956.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_070956&quot; title=&quot;20170624_070956&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_072310.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_072310&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_072310.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_072310&quot; title=&quot;20170624_072310&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_075850.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_075850&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_075850.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_075850&quot; title=&quot;20170624_075850&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_082511.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_082511&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_082511.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_082511&quot; title=&quot;20170624_082511&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_083210.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_083210&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_083210.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_083210&quot; title=&quot;20170624_083210&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_083327.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_083327&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_083327.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_083327&quot; title=&quot;20170624_083327&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_123533.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_123533&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_123533.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_123533&quot; title=&quot;20170624_123533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_153049.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_153049&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_153049.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_153049&quot; title=&quot;20170624_153049&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_153422.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170624_153422&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/20170624_153422.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170624_153422&quot; title=&quot;20170624_153422&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/header_lavaredo.jpg&quot; title=&quot;header_lavaredo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/header_lavaredo.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;header_lavaredo&quot; title=&quot;header_lavaredo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/lavaredo/mappa_lut.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mappa_lut&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/lavaredo/mappa_lut.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mappa_lut&quot; title=&quot;mappa_lut&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">Lavaredo Ultra Trail is a 120km ultra trail race with 5800m of elevation gain in the Dolomites.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ultra Trail Tai Mo Shan TTF 荃打火 115k</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/ttf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ultra Trail Tai Mo Shan TTF 荃打火 115k" /><published>2017-01-22T19:45:13-08:00</published><updated>2017-01-22T19:45:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/01/ttf</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/01/ttf.html">&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Pre-Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at Hong Kong in the afternoon of Dec. 30th. After I picked up the racer pack at Fo Tan (火炭), I walked around downtown and did some sightseeing in the evening. I may have lingered on the street of the Pearl of the Orient too long that my hamstring felt a little tight. Fortunately after a good night's sleep the slight discomfort went away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race would start at 4pm, so I enjoyed a leisurely morning the next day. After a last-minute carb loading lunch at a brunch place, I headed to Tsuen King Circuit (荃灣荃景圍遊樂場) at 2:30pm. I got my mandatory gear checked by the volunteers, checked in my two drop bags for Tai Tong and the finish line, and I was ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20161231_154151.jpg&quot; width=60%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Tsuen Wan 荃灣 (0km) - Tai Tong 大棠 (65km)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right after the start, the course climbed some 350 meters to Lian Fa Shan (蓮花山) via Shek Lung Kung (石龍拱), before dropping to CP1 Farm Milk 農場鮮奶 (13km) at 5:35pm. The distance was a bit off for CP1. It was listed as 13km, but really just around 10k from start. I rested for 10 minutes at the check point, and headed back on the course. The next 5k was relatively flat on paved road and I was able to run most of them at a pace of around 10min/mile. Afterwards the elevation rose again to 390m at Tin Fu Tsai Shan (田夫仔山) and I went back to power hiking. From Tin Fu Tsai Shan the course descended all the way back to sea level at CP2 Sham Tseng 深井 (30km). I felt fairly good and passed quite a few runners along the way, arriving at the check point&amp;nbsp;at 7:51pm. There's a big gathering at Sham Tseng, and the volunteers were serving fresh roast goose and noodles, along with the usual race food. I must have eaten at least 20 pieces of goose. If there has to be a criticism about the race, it is that the check points were too cozy, that it was hard for me to head back to running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20161231_195900.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent 30 minutes at Sham Tseng and set out again at 8:20pm. The elevation change was mostly moderate and I made good progress, arriving at CP4 Tai Tong 大棠 (65km) at 1:51am. By then my quads were a bit sore from pounding the paved paths and hard-surface trails, but overall I felt good. While sitting there resting I did the math: I covered 65km in 10 hours, so I was pretty confident that I could finish in 20 hours, and maybe even 18 hours. Boy, I couldn't be more wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20170101_000614.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Tai Tong 大棠 (65km) - Fo Tan 火炭 (115km)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After leaving Tai Tong, the course followed the Tai Tong Shan Road briefly and then followed the trail to Sze Pai Shek Shan (四排石山). Sze Pai Shek Shan is really four hill and the trail was basically on the ridge. Although the highest hilltop is only 290m, the ups and downs were quite annoying. It took me around one and a half hours to reach SCP5 (Semi Check Point, where volunteers check you in with a mobile app). Afterwards the trail dropped sharply by 100m, ascended again to Cheung Ngau Shan (掌牛山) at 220m, and finally dropping back to sea level. It was at night and tall weeds grew right next to the trail, making it hard to see what I was stepping onto. I lost my footing a number of times, but fortunately only suffered some minor scratches. After I finally got out of the single tracks&amp;nbsp;and rejoined the paved road, I missed a turn where the course followed a pedestrian subway. I had to backtrack and lost another 15 minutes because of that. I arrived at CP5 Fung Kat Heung 逢吉鄉 (78km) at 5:31am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Fung Kat Heung, the course followed the ridge all the way up to Kai Kung Leng 圭角山 at 585m, then dropped back to 50m above sea level at SCP6 Ta Shek Wu 打石湖 (85km). I handled the climb okay, but I started to struggle at the descent as my quads gave out. The steep slope on hard-surface trail certaintly didn't do me any favor and my pace at the descent was even slower than at the ascent. I pulled into Ta Shek Wu at 7:49am. After a brief rest I took off again, climbing 500m to Tai To Yan (大刀屻). I took a couple of gels and seemed to recover a little. Quad weren't hurting as bad so I managed to pick up the pace on the descent to CP6. I pulled into CP6 Kadoorie Farm and Botanic Garden 嘉道理農場 (93km) at 10:24am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/GY6A4860.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after leaving the check point, the battery of my Fenix2 drained and I had to run by feels The climb to the highest point of the race, the 780m Sze Fong Shan (四方山), took me two hours. When I finally reached that point, the course took a steep dip down a side trail. I had struggled throughout the race with those descents on hard-surface trails, and at that point my quads were completed wrecked. While I was stumbling down the hill, racers were passing me left and right. I arrived at CP7 Wun Yiu 碗窰 (105km) exhausted at 1:40pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC04088.jpg&quot; width=60%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Yours truly on Sze Fong Shan&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was actually surprised that it was not even 2pm when I got to the check point. This got my hope up that I had a chance to finish the race in 24 hours. There was one more hill, the 640m Grassy Hill 草山, to climb in the last segment. It took another me 80 minutes and I was finally up on top at 3:13pm. The way down was mostly on paved road, and I got an adrenaline rush closer to the finish line, so despite my quads discomfort, I picked up the pace, shuffled down as fast as I could and crossed the line at 4:02pm, and the finish time is 24:02:57. I was a little bummed that I had missed 24 hours by less than 3 minutes, but ultimately I was more than happy to have finished this very tough race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC00143.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Record:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://livetrack.sportsystem.hk/utmt201617/livetrack_detail.html?bibno=0815&amp;amp;lang=en&quot;&gt;http://livetrack.sportsystem.hk/utmt201617/livetrack_detail.html?bibno=0815&amp;amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/15844472_1216100818465969_544982904154220324_o.jpg&quot; title=&quot;15844472_1216100818465969_544982904154220324_o&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/15844472_1216100818465969_544982904154220324_o.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;15844472_1216100818465969_544982904154220324_o&quot; title=&quot;15844472_1216100818465969_544982904154220324_o&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/15875144_1864013387179562_9062079254700630009_o.jpg&quot; title=&quot;15875144_1864013387179562_9062079254700630009_o&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/15875144_1864013387179562_9062079254700630009_o.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;15875144_1864013387179562_9062079254700630009_o&quot; title=&quot;15875144_1864013387179562_9062079254700630009_o&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/2016-12-31_UTMT TTF Start Point_(72).JPG&quot; title=&quot;2016-12-31_UTMT TTF Start Point_(72)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/2016-12-31_UTMT TTF Start Point_(72).JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;2016-12-31_UTMT TTF Start Point_(72)&quot; title=&quot;2016-12-31_UTMT TTF Start Point_(72)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20161230_161031.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20161230_161031&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/20161230_161031.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20161230_161031&quot; title=&quot;20161230_161031&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20161231_154151.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20161231_154151&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/20161231_154151.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20161231_154151&quot; title=&quot;20161231_154151&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20161231_195900.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20161231_195900&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/20161231_195900.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20161231_195900&quot; title=&quot;20161231_195900&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20161231_195917.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20161231_195917&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/20161231_195917.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20161231_195917&quot; title=&quot;20161231_195917&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/2017-01-01 09-43-53 - 1746.JPG&quot; title=&quot;2017-01-01 09-43-53 - 1746&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/2017-01-01 09-43-53 - 1746.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;2017-01-01 09-43-53 - 1746&quot; title=&quot;2017-01-01 09-43-53 - 1746&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20170101_000614.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170101_000614&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/20170101_000614.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170101_000614&quot; title=&quot;20170101_000614&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/20170101_021455.jpg&quot; title=&quot;20170101_021455&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/20170101_021455.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;20170101_021455&quot; title=&quot;20170101_021455&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/2048_465ec175f011014216bd9fe8e78e2016.jpg&quot; title=&quot;2048_465ec175f011014216bd9fe8e78e2016&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/2048_465ec175f011014216bd9fe8e78e2016.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;2048_465ec175f011014216bd9fe8e78e2016&quot; title=&quot;2048_465ec175f011014216bd9fe8e78e2016&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/2048_539d8726a38fae82ee8da0b9f1b7a3dc.JPG&quot; title=&quot;2048_539d8726a38fae82ee8da0b9f1b7a3dc&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/2048_539d8726a38fae82ee8da0b9f1b7a3dc.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;2048_539d8726a38fae82ee8da0b9f1b7a3dc&quot; title=&quot;2048_539d8726a38fae82ee8da0b9f1b7a3dc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC00143.JPG&quot; title=&quot;DSC00143&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/DSC00143.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC00143&quot; title=&quot;DSC00143&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC04076.JPG&quot; title=&quot;DSC04076&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/DSC04076.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC04076&quot; title=&quot;DSC04076&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC04088.JPG&quot; title=&quot;DSC04088&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/DSC04088.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC04088&quot; title=&quot;DSC04088&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC_4490.JPG&quot; title=&quot;DSC_4490&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/DSC_4490.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_4490&quot; title=&quot;DSC_4490&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/DSC_7722.JPG&quot; title=&quot;DSC_7722&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/DSC_7722.JPG&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_7722&quot; title=&quot;DSC_7722&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/GY6A4860.jpg&quot; title=&quot;GY6A4860&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/GY6A4860.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;GY6A4860&quot; title=&quot;GY6A4860&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/TTF_ver3.03-01.jpg&quot; title=&quot;TTF_ver3.03-01&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/TTF_ver3.03-01.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;TTF_ver3.03-01&quot; title=&quot;TTF_ver3.03-01&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/TTFver4.04-01.jpg&quot; title=&quot;TTFver4.04-01&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/TTFver4.04-01.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;TTFver4.04-01&quot; title=&quot;TTFver4.04-01&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/Tai_Mo_Shan.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Tai_Mo_Shan&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/Tai_Mo_Shan.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;Tai_Mo_Shan&quot; title=&quot;Tai_Mo_Shan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/UTMT-328.jpg&quot; title=&quot;UTMT-328&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/UTMT-328.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;UTMT-328&quot; title=&quot;UTMT-328&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/ttf/UTMT210617_Certificate_T0815_.jpg&quot; title=&quot;UTMT210617_Certificate_T0815_&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/ttf/UTMT210617_Certificate_T0815_.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;UTMT210617_Certificate_T0815_&quot; title=&quot;UTMT210617_Certificate_T0815_&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2016 Philadelphia Marathon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/11/philadelphia-marathon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2016 Philadelphia Marathon" /><published>2016-11-30T19:45:13-08:00</published><updated>2016-11-30T19:45:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/philadelphia-marathon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/11/philadelphia-marathon.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;table style=&quot;width:80%&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Goal&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th&gt;Completed&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;A&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;3:10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;B&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;3:10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;C&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;&lt;3:15&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started training after I got back from my summer backpacking trip. For the most part, I followed Pfitzinger's 12/55 plan. Despite the unusually warm weather in Toronto, I would often skip recovery runs, so my weekly mileage was&amp;nbsp;never over 45 miles. From the beginning, my runs felt more sluggish than I had liked and I had to dial down the pace for workouts. I still kept BQ as my A goal, but realistically I knew chances were slim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ran the Toronto half marathon on Oct. 16th as a tune-up race&amp;nbsp;and managed to finish just under 1:30 (1:29:48). According to McMillan's formula, that would put me at around 3:10 for the full marathon.&amp;nbsp;Weather wasn't perfect that day. It was quite warm, and it was drizzling for the first half an hour or so. This got my hope up a little bit, that maybe if weather would be perfect at Philly, I might still have a shot at 3:05.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week before the race, I traveled to Nashville for an academic conference (INFORMS), and stayed there until Wednesday. I was able to get out and ran my last 12 miler on Sunday, but then caught a cold the next day. It wasn't serious, but enough to keep me from running for the next 3 days. I tried 2 miles at marathon pace on Thursday, and it did not feel right at all. It was a bummer but there's not anything I could do about it, so I decided to just run the race and hope for the best.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Pre-Race&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at Philadelphia on Saturday afternoon. It was a beautiful day, with high in the 70s. I walked to the exhibition center and picked up my bib. Afterward I headed to Chinatown for dinner. I&amp;nbsp;was delighted to find out my favorite noodle place was still open, although they had since jacked up the price for quite a bit. For some last minute card loading, I had some noodle soup with extra noodles, and bought some Gatorade and bread on my way back to hotel. I watched some college football and went to bed at around 10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 4:30am on race day, and had some coffee and bread. At 5:30, I boarded the free hotel shuttle to the start line. It was about 30 degrees outside, but I still decided to wear singlet and shorts. Because why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Mile 1 to 13&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Race started promptly at 7. My fenix 2 was off by quite a bit the first couple miles, so I wasn't able to tell what my exact pace was. It was a problem throughout the race, as I wasn't able to tell my expected finish time. I had to take a quick leak at the second mile and wasted 30 seconds. I picked the pace up a little bit around 4 miles on Chestnut street. &amp;nbsp;I was following the 3:15 pace group &amp;nbsp;for 2&amp;nbsp;miles on the narrow street and decided to pass them just before crossing the Schuykill River. There was still a large spectator showup despite the cold. My 10k split was 46:12. My pace was 10 seconds slower than what I had in mind, and I was already feeling some fatigue at such early stage. So mentally I adjusted my goal to 3:10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there we entered University City and encountered a couple of rolling hills&amp; and a more significant one t before the zoo. I struggled a little bit. The 3:15 group almost caught up. The downhill immediately following was a great relief and I was able to stay ahead of that group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then proceeded to the Fairmount Park. There were some changes to the course this year. They got rid of the Falls Bridge turnaround, and added a couple of miles in the Fairmount Park. It felt a bit lonely at that section. There were fewer spectators, and we were reduced to smaller groups of 3 or 4 runners. I passed the half way point at 1:36:13. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Mile 14 to 20&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then headed back to the art museum, and began the long run towards Manayunk on Kelly Drive. I picked up the pace and tried to keep it at around 7:10. I managed it the first couple of miles but then I first experienced the full force of the wind. The first half we were more or less shielded by the buildings. It was frustrating trying to power up running into that 30 mph wind. My pace dropped to 7:20 again, and by that time I knew that I would be lucky if I could pull up a 3:10 finish. My left hamstring also started to tighten. It had not interfered with my running yet, but I knew it would be a problem later in the race.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I was still moving fine and reached 30k at 2:16:52. Kelly Drive wasn't easy for spectators to get to, but the crowds at East Falls and Manayunk were great. I got some much needed adrenaline pump with their loud cheers. There were guys giving out beer shots at Manayunk. It was unfortunate that my stomach could barely handle the gels, so I had to pass that offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Mile 21 to Finish&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the turnaround at Manayunk, we started the long way back to the finish line. By that time, my hamstring felt worse, and it was just a matter of time before it cramped. To make things worse, I was still running against the wind for some reason. My pace dropped to 7:30, and I was exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the 24th mile, the expected cramp finally happened. My moan must have sounded terrible, as multiple runners from the other direction came to me and asked if I needed assistance. I waved them off and wasted a couple of minutes desperately trying to stretch it out. I managed to get that under control but 8:30 pace was now the fastest I could muster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last 2 miles was all about survival. I had nothing left in the tank, and every cell of my body was screaming stop.  I used all my mental power to persuade myself to keep running. After what seemed like an eternity, I spotted what I thought was the finish line. It turned out that because the wind, they did not erect the arch, so there was just a digital board that showed time. It was a great relief that I was indeed right and I crossed the line at 3:16:58.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Post-Race&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt completed wrecked immediately after the race, and had to sit for a while just to gather enough energy to walk to the truck and collect my checked bag. But after a couple hours I felt just fine. My muscles were sore but I could walk with no problem (stark contrast to my previous 3 marathon attempts). I also started doing recovery runs three days later. I was not too thrilled about the time, but under the weather condition it's not too bad. It does mean that I have to run a spring marathon in order to BQ for 2018. For now my plan is to run Ottawa marathon on May 29th. Here is hoping that it won't be too warm on race day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strava Activity:&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/780954926&quot;&gt;https://www.strava.com/activities/780954926&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0034 (1).jpg&quot; title=&quot;0034 (1)&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0034 (1).jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0034 (1)&quot; title=&quot;0034 (1)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0046.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0046&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0046.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0046&quot; title=&quot;0046&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0047.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0047&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0047.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0047&quot; title=&quot;0047&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0051.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0051&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0051.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0051&quot; title=&quot;0051&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0055.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0055&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0055.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0055&quot; title=&quot;0055&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0076.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0076&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0076.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0076&quot; title=&quot;0076&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0096.jpg&quot; title=&quot;0096&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/philadelphia-marathon/0096.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;0096&quot; title=&quot;0096&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Denali</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/denali.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Denali" /><published>2016-09-09T20:45:13-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T20:45:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/denali</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/denali.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Aug. 27th to Aug. 31st 2016, I spent five days backpacking in Denali National Park, Alaska.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A backpacking trip in Denali is hard to prepare. They have one of the most strict &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/dena/planyourvisit/backpacking-guide.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;quota systems&lt;/a&gt; I have had to go through. The park is divided into a few dozen units. Instead of controlling for the number of hikers starting every day, they restrict the number of people that can spend the night in the unit every day. Quota number is different between different units, most commonly 4 or 8. Permits can only be applied in person, and can be applied at most one day in advance. It is further complicated if the planned route involves river crossing, depending on weather condition, the river may not be crossable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, &lt;a href=&quot;http://caltopo.com/m/V0S0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;my plan&lt;/a&gt; was to hike to Mcgonagall Pass then follow Clearwater Creek and cross Muldrow Glacier back to Eielson visitor center. When I arrived at the backcountry office and talked to the rangers, I was told that it had been raining a lot, and nobody had successfully crossed McKinley River without a boat in this season. I had to scrap my plan, look at the units map and their availability, and figure out an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still wanted to go to the general area south of the park road between Eielson and Wonder Lake. I was really fortunate that there happened to be a campsite available for Wonder Lake for that night. It was usually full. Booking it in advance is strongly recommended. So based on the availability of backcountry units, I decided to stay at Wonder Lake for the night. Then explore Sunset and Sunrise Glacier at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/dena/planyourvisit/unit12.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;unit 12&lt;/a&gt; on day 1. Get into Glacier Creek valley&amp;nbsp;via Contact Creek, cross Muldrow Glacier to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/dena/planyourvisit/unit19.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;unit 19&lt;/a&gt;, camp there for 3 nights and hike into the valleys there. I also added 2 nights at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/dena/planyourvisit/unit13.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;unit 13&lt;/a&gt; for some basecamp day hikes. This is what I actually did (it's not GPS tracking data. I just drew it for illustration):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class = 'embed-container'&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://caltopo.com/m/LP7T&quot; style=&quot;width: 80%;border:none;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Getting In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denali is 5 hours drive away from Anchorage. I took the morning &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alaskashuttle.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Alaska/Yukon Trails&lt;/a&gt; shuttle and arrived at Wilderness Access Center (WAC) at noon. I spent a hour working out the route, and then sat through the mandatory video orientation. Expect to spend at least 2 hours in the backcountry office. Rangers usually have spare bear spray available for loan, as most people who brought in bear spray wouldn't use it. Gas canister however, was only available in town. It was already 2:50pm and the last camper bus would leave at 4:05pm. While there's  a 2 mile trail going to town, I unwisely decided to ride the Princess shuttle, which turned out to be much slower than walking. I was really frustrated when I got back to WAC at 4:15pm. Miraculously the bus was late and didn't arrive till 4:30. I changed clothes, put my stuffs in a locker and boarded the bus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were only 2 passengers on the last camper bus. When the French dude got off at Salvage River, it was just me and the driver. We were fortunate to see quite a few animals, including a grizzly near Eielson. Not in a hurry, we sat there watching it for half an hour. I arrived at Wonder Lake at 9:30pm, hastily pitched tent, had some dinner and went to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06778.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waking up at 5:30am, I ate breakfast in a haste and boarded the 6:30am bus. An hour later I arrived at Eielson visitor center. I took my time using the washroom and filling water inside the cozy building, knowing beyond here it would be true wilderness. At 8am, I left the building and dropped down to the Thorofare river bar. There should be a well maintained trail dropping all the way down to the river bar, but I somehow missed it and had to do some bushwhacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06804.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less than one hour into the hike, when I just turned into the valley, I spotted my first bear in the bushes on the left about 100 yards away. We had a brief eye contact and the bear seemed cool. I managed to speak in a (relatively) calm voice and retreated back about half a mile. I then looked for the bear but it was nowhere to be seen. So I moved back in and now stuck as far right as it was possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soon the river met the cliff and instead of climbing up the hill to reroute, I decided to cross directly. Water was muddy from the dirty glacier, so it wasn't easy to gauge the depth, but first crossing was quite easy. As a result I grew much more confident. When I encountered the second crossing, thinking it must be easier as it was further upstream, I decided lightly to cross again. This time water was deeper and faster, I felt it mid-crossing, but unwisely pressed on. I then lost my footing and fell face down. Fortunately I was able to gain back the foot a second later and made it to the other side. However I lost my glasses after the fall (I carried a spare), and I kicked myself for being so reckless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another hour or so, I reached the intersection of Sunrise Creek. I ventured into the valley for a few hundred yards, but the valley was quite narrow and deep, and I didn't think I would be able to continue much further. So I retracted to the intersection and kept hiking towards Sunset Glacier. Before reaching Fault Creek, there came the third river crossing, and this time it couldn't be avoided. More cautious, I walked up and down for half an hour and finally found a crossable spot. My foot were numb from the freezing glacier water and it was not pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06812.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afterwards as I hiked further upstream, the river actually grew faster and deeper, and I didn't feel comfortable crossing again. As a result, there were places where I was forced to climb up steep hills to get around the river. At around 2pm, I reached Sunset Glacier, covered with dirt. After walking for an hour or so, not expecting to see anything more, I turned around and head back. I was hoping to camp next to Contact Creek, but there were a lot of recent diggings that might be the doing of bears, so I pitched my tent south of the creek on tundra.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06826.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day I followed Contact Creek to the top of the pass overlooking Glacier Creek. The climb was moderate and the view at the top was gorgeous. I literally shed a few tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06876.jpg&quot;, width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then follow Wolverine Creek down to Glacier Creek. Shortly after Green Point, I headed west to cross Muldrow Glacier. Don't be deceived by the distance on the map, there were a lot of ups and downs underneath and would take at least 2 to 3 hours to get to the other side. Glacier is covered with dirt for the most part, so as long as common caution is exercised, it is not really dangerous. I found that sticking to higher ridges as far as possible instead of dropping down was more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06934.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the other side of the glacier at 5pm, and decided to take advantage of the good weather and hike a couple more hours. From there the route roughly followed Private Creek, but it was not necessary to drop down and bushwhack. Higher up on the hills, terrain was mostly dry tundra and fairly easy to walk on. In fact, in most part of valleys bushwhacking could be avoided by climbing up to the higher tundra platform. So I was able to make good progress and reached first fork of Clearwater Creek at 8pm. For some reason, I decided to drop down to the creek. Though yelling as loud as I could, I met it my second bear after a turn. We were barely 10 yards away and both were shocked. The bear turned and ran away. I turned and walked back out the valley. After 5 minutes or so, I determined that the bear had left the area and vowed not to drop down to the creek unless necessary. Walking for another hour into the valley, I found a relatively flat area on the tundra platform and called it a day. I took water from down the creek and pitched my tent up there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06982.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued hiking into the valley. It was a beautiful sunny day and I was in great spirit not having to whack bushes. I reached the end of the valley shortly after 1pm.&amp;nbsp;All the ridges looked quite steep. But there's plenty of time left so I decided to try to climb from one side. It was covered with rocks and boulders of different sizes, and they were not&amp;nbsp;unstable. It took me 2 hours going close to the top. The last climb looked really dangerous and I called it quits. Going down was harder, I lost balance a couple times and got some scratches as result, but was able to get down safely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07050.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then retracted out the valley. There's a saddle on the west side of the ridge, so I just climbed over the pass and arrived at the second valley. I pitched my tent on the higher platform and called it a day.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ridge at the end of second valley was much easier to climb. There was tundra on the hill and rocks were firm. There was a moderate flat area to rest on the top. Views from the top of the two valleys were similar, both facing Muldrow Glacier, Mt. Brooks and nearby snowy peaks.&amp;nbsp; I lingered for some time marveling at the view and taking selfies, then started my way back to Eielson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07102.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking the short cut through the saddle, I made it to Private Creek around 9pm. It made a lovely campsite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07166.jpg&quot; width=90%&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I received a Delorme Inreach message from Rani, reminding me the northern light in the evening. Never seen one before, I set up the alarm and reluctantly got out of the tent at 2:30am. And it was cold! I did see the northern light, but I lasted no more than 5 minutes before hurrying back into tent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07168.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next morning I found that my shoes, put inside the fly, was frozen rock solid. It took more than one hour exposed to the sun for them to unfroze. It just showed how cold it was last night.&amp;nbsp; By that time I started missing the modern amenities, so I decided to forgo the last two nights at unit 13, and hike out the same day. By my calculation, crossing Muldrow would take roughly three hours and I should have more than enough time to reach Eielson before the last bus leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second time crossing Muldrow turned out to be easier, and I made it out to Glacier Creek at noon. It seemed I had some time to spare, so I decided to hike further into the valley and take a look at the Glacier from another angle. I severely underestimated the distance however. It took me close to two hours to reach there. Thinking the last bus leaves at 7pm, I hurried out. Fortunately terrain wasn't too rough, and I basically waded through the creek without hesitation for like ten times. I got back to Thorofare River bar at 5pm and to the visitor center at 6:25pm. Apparently the last bus would actually leave at 6:30pm, I hurriedly hopped on the bus, and headed back to WAC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07192.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus got to WAC at 10pm and it was already dark. I managed to get a ride to town from a Polish couple from the same bus. Princess Lodge still had a room left so I gladly took it. I haven't been eating or drinking for 4 hours and was on the verge of collapse. I walked to the Subway, got a $16 sub packed with meat, then headed to the liquor store and got a six pack. Lying on hotel bed, eating sub, drinking beer, and watching Pawn Stars, it was a beautiful night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06747.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06747&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06747.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06747&quot; title=&quot;DSC06747&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06754.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06754&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06754.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06754&quot; title=&quot;DSC06754&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06756.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06756&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06756.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06756&quot; title=&quot;DSC06756&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06758.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06758&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06758.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06758&quot; title=&quot;DSC06758&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06761.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06761&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06761.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06761&quot; title=&quot;DSC06761&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06772.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06772&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06772.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06772&quot; title=&quot;DSC06772&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06778.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06778&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06778.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06778&quot; title=&quot;DSC06778&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06780.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06780&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06780.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06780&quot; title=&quot;DSC06780&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06793.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06793&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06793.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06793&quot; title=&quot;DSC06793&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06804.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06804&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06804.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06804&quot; title=&quot;DSC06804&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06805.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06805&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06805.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06805&quot; title=&quot;DSC06805&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06812.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06812&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06812.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06812&quot; title=&quot;DSC06812&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06814.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06814&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06814.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06814&quot; title=&quot;DSC06814&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06815.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06815&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06815.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06815&quot; title=&quot;DSC06815&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06816.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06816&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06816.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06816&quot; title=&quot;DSC06816&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06826.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06826&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06826.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06826&quot; title=&quot;DSC06826&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06834.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06834&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06834.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06834&quot; title=&quot;DSC06834&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06836.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06836&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06836.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06836&quot; title=&quot;DSC06836&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06845.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06845&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06845.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06845&quot; title=&quot;DSC06845&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06851.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06851&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06851.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06851&quot; title=&quot;DSC06851&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06876.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06876&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06876.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06876&quot; title=&quot;DSC06876&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06883.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06883&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06883.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06883&quot; title=&quot;DSC06883&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06887.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06887&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06887.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06887&quot; title=&quot;DSC06887&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06905.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06905&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06905.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06905&quot; title=&quot;DSC06905&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06909.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06909&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06909.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06909&quot; title=&quot;DSC06909&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06929.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06929&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06929.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06929&quot; title=&quot;DSC06929&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06934.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06934&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06934.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06934&quot; title=&quot;DSC06934&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06944.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06944&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06944.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06944&quot; title=&quot;DSC06944&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06950.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06950&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06950.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06950&quot; title=&quot;DSC06950&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06954.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06954&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06954.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06954&quot; title=&quot;DSC06954&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06960.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06960&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06960.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06960&quot; title=&quot;DSC06960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06961.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06961&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06961.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06961&quot; title=&quot;DSC06961&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06969.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06969&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06969.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06969&quot; title=&quot;DSC06969&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06975.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06975&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06975.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06975&quot; title=&quot;DSC06975&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06977.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06977&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06977.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06977&quot; title=&quot;DSC06977&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06982.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06982&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06982.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06982&quot; title=&quot;DSC06982&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06993.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06993&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06993.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06993&quot; title=&quot;DSC06993&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC06999.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06999&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC06999.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06999&quot; title=&quot;DSC06999&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07008.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07008&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07008.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07008&quot; title=&quot;DSC07008&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07026.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07026&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07026.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07026&quot; title=&quot;DSC07026&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07031.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07031&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07031.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07031&quot; title=&quot;DSC07031&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07040.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07040&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07040.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07040&quot; title=&quot;DSC07040&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07050.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07050&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07050.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07050&quot; title=&quot;DSC07050&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07060.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07060&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07060.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07060&quot; title=&quot;DSC07060&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07065.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07065&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07065.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07065&quot; title=&quot;DSC07065&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07077.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07077&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07077.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07077&quot; title=&quot;DSC07077&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07102.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07102&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07102.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07102&quot; title=&quot;DSC07102&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07112.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07112&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07112.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07112&quot; title=&quot;DSC07112&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07145.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07145&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07145.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07145&quot; title=&quot;DSC07145&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07149.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07149&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07149.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07149&quot; title=&quot;DSC07149&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07157.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07157&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07157.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07157&quot; title=&quot;DSC07157&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07163.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07163&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07163.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07163&quot; title=&quot;DSC07163&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07166.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07166&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07166.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07166&quot; title=&quot;DSC07166&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07168.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07168&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07168.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07168&quot; title=&quot;DSC07168&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07180.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07180&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07180.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07180&quot; title=&quot;DSC07180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07185.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07185&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07185.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07185&quot; title=&quot;DSC07185&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07188.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07188&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07188.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07188&quot; title=&quot;DSC07188&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07192.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07192&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07192.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07192&quot; title=&quot;DSC07192&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07197.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07197&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07197.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07197&quot; title=&quot;DSC07197&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07202.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07202&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07202.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07202&quot; title=&quot;DSC07202&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07210.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07210&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07210.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07210&quot; title=&quot;DSC07210&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07216.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07216&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07216.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07216&quot; title=&quot;DSC07216&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07219.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07219&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07219.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07219&quot; title=&quot;DSC07219&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07220.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07220&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07220.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07220&quot; title=&quot;DSC07220&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/denali/DSC07223.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC07223&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/denali/DSC07223.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC07223&quot; title=&quot;DSC07223&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">From Aug. 27th to Aug. 31st 2016, I spent five days backpacking in Denali National Park, Alaska.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chilkoot Trail</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/chilkoot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chilkoot Trail" /><published>2016-09-09T20:45:13-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-09T20:45:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/chilkoot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/chilkoot.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chilkoot is a 33 mile trail from Dyea, AK to Bennett, BC. My friend Rani and I did the hike from Aug. 22nd to Aug. 24th in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Chilkoot Trail was a route used by stampeders during Klondike gold rush over 100 years ago. The stampeders would come by boat to Skagway, AK, and head to Bennett, BC via Chilkoot Pass, the rare ice-free pass in the area. From Bennett they would then build boats and attempt to sail to Dawson on Yukon River. Several tent cities were established along the trail, and artifacts are still scattering around now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06695.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a quota of 50 hikers per day that get over Chilkoot Pass. Fortunately the demand wasn' too high. I called Parks Canada a month prior to our trip, was put on wait list at first, but soon got two spots for Aug. 23rd. Permits should be picked up at ranger's station at Skagway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finished our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mountain-du.com/2016/09/donjek-route/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Donjek hike&lt;/a&gt; on Aug. 21st, and left for Skagway from Whitehorse via bus the next morning. We booked both the bus and the train back to Skagway from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yukonalaskatouristtours.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Yukon Alaska Tourist Tour&lt;/a&gt;. It came down to about 160 USD per person.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a US Immigration at Fraser, BC. Because of my foreigner status, the bus had to wait for half an hour for me to clear immigration (sorry). We arrived at Skagway at noon, picked up our permits and had a cozy rest day at this small town packed with tourists coming off cruises.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/20160821_134709.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Skagway, AK&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our Donjek hike, Rani and I realized that neither of us was fond of waking up early. So we conveniently booked the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Trumooreservices/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dyea-Chilkoot Trail Transport&lt;/a&gt; at 10am. Dyea is a short ride from Skagway and we started the hike at 10:30am. The 12 miles from Dyea to Sheep Camp is not difficult. After Donjek, that was a welcoming change. We arrived at Sheep Camp at around 4:30pm, and there were already over 30 other hikers there. Fortunately there were enough campsites. Campsites at Sheep Camp were platforms but didn't have hooks. It is mildly inconvenient to pitch my Fly Creek tent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 7 pm, a ranger came to camp and briefed the weather forecasts and trail conditions going up Chilkoot Pass the next day. According to the forecast, it's highly likely that it would rain for the whole day. Having had a fairly easy day, we were not too concerned about it, and decided to push to Lindeman the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06705.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got up at 6am and surely it was raining. By the time we gathered our stuffs and headed to the shelter for breakfast, we were the only ones left at camp. We left Sheep Camp at 8am and headed towards the pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were making good progress at the beginning. Biggest complaint was that it felt too warm wearing the rain jacket. After the scales though, temperature dropped down significantly and we started scrambling up the boulders. It took us an hour or so getting over the boulder field and we were supposed to see a shelter on the pass. It became quite foggy and we couldn't see beyond a few feet away. I was worried that we missed the shelter until we heard the humming sound. It was the electric generator at the ranger's house, and the shelter was right next to it. We walked into the shelter and it was packed. Only then did I realize that I felt really cold. The nice lady from Parks Canada put a heater in the room so I was able to warm up a little bit. It was funny that of all the hikers we saw, everyone looked miserable. It just showed that there's still a lot to be desired from the waterproof fabric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06707.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We stayed in the shelter for a little less than an hour and decided to move on. I was still feeling a bit cold but thought once we started hiking again it should be fine. So we started our hike down the pass. After the Stone Crib, the terrain got easier, but still above tree line and feeling chilly. At around 2pm, we passed Happy Camp, where most other hikers would spend the night. Three hours later we arrived at Lindeman. Lindeman campground is huge. Upper and lower part are 5 minutes' walk away, and each has a cooking shelter and at least 20 campsites. Apparently the standard 5 day itinerary would skip Lindeman and camp at Bare Loon Lake on the 4th day, so we were the only two people camping at upper Lindeman for the night. It's a shame that such a nice campground was not utilized by more people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06722.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we made it to Bennett at noon after three hours of hike, barely breaking a sweat. We boarded the train that left for Skagway at 3:10pm Alaska time. The next day we hopped on the ferry to Juneau, and from Juneau took the flight to Anchorage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/20160824_172805.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06682.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06682&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06682.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06682&quot; title=&quot;DSC06682&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06685.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06685&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06685.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06685&quot; title=&quot;DSC06685&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06687.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06687&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06687.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06687&quot; title=&quot;DSC06687&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06688.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06688&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06688.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06688&quot; title=&quot;DSC06688&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06691.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06691&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06691.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06691&quot; title=&quot;DSC06691&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06692.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06692&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06692.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06692&quot; title=&quot;DSC06692&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06693.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06693&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06693.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06693&quot; title=&quot;DSC06693&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06694.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06694&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06694.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06694&quot; title=&quot;DSC06694&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06695.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06695&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06695.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06695&quot; title=&quot;DSC06695&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06699.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06699&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06699.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06699&quot; title=&quot;DSC06699&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06704.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06704&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06704.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06704&quot; title=&quot;DSC06704&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06705.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06705&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06705.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06705&quot; title=&quot;DSC06705&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06706.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06706&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06706.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06706&quot; title=&quot;DSC06706&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06707.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06707&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06707.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06707&quot; title=&quot;DSC06707&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06708.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06708&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06708.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06708&quot; title=&quot;DSC06708&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06712.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06712&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06712.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06712&quot; title=&quot;DSC06712&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06713.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06713&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06713.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06713&quot; title=&quot;DSC06713&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06715.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06715&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06715.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06715&quot; title=&quot;DSC06715&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06716.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06716&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06716.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06716&quot; title=&quot;DSC06716&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06717.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06717&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06717.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06717&quot; title=&quot;DSC06717&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06718.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06718&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06718.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06718&quot; title=&quot;DSC06718&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06720.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06720&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06720.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06720&quot; title=&quot;DSC06720&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06722.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06722&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06722.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06722&quot; title=&quot;DSC06722&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06723.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06723&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06723.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06723&quot; title=&quot;DSC06723&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06730.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06730&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06730.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06730&quot; title=&quot;DSC06730&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06736.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06736&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06736.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06736&quot; title=&quot;DSC06736&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06738.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06738&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06738.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06738&quot; title=&quot;DSC06738&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06740.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06740&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/DSC06740.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06740&quot; title=&quot;DSC06740&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/mmexport1472177235278.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1472177235278&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/mmexport1472177235278.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1472177235278&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1472177235278&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/chilkoot/mmexport1472177257429.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1472177257429&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/chilkoot/mmexport1472177257429.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1472177257429&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1472177257429&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">Chilkoot is a 33 mile trail from Dyea, AK to Bennett, BC. My friend Rani and I did the hike from Aug. 22nd to Aug. 24th in 2016.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Donjek Route</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/donjek-route.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Donjek Route" /><published>2016-09-04T15:49:25-07:00</published><updated>2016-09-04T15:49:25-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2016/09/donjek-route</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2016/09/donjek-route.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donjek Route is a 60 mile backcountry route in Kluane National Park, Yukon Territory. My friend Rani and I did the route from Aug. 13th to Aug. 19th in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Trip Planning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not a lot of people have done the route. Fortunately, a number of them have uploaded their GPS tracks. We built our map in Alltrails using mainly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zoology.ubc.ca/~louca/HomePage/lib/php/index.php?section=Outdoors&quot;&gt;Stilianos Louca's gpx file&lt;/a&gt;, and found it to be fairly accurate. We also downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.everytrail.com/view_trip.php?trip_id=1776104&quot;&gt;scottw66's track on everytrail&lt;/a&gt;. His route did not cross Duke River, but instead followed the river downstream. In our hike, we eventually did the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a little tricky to estimate the number of days we would need. We took into account that the route was mostly off-trail, but we were also prepared to hike over 10 hours every day. In the end, we decided that 7 days should be a good estimate, and would carry an extra day of food for safety. Kluane is grizzly country and bear canister is mandatory. We carried our own BearVaults.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Difficulty&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the hardest hike I have ever done. Most of the route is off-trail. Navigation is not a huge problem because of the dramatic topography, but there's a lot of bush (and tree) whacking. Descent of Hoge pass is also quite difficult.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kluane National Park is a couple of hours drive from Whitehorse, YT. While Whitehorse is the largest city in the territory, it has a population of only twenty thousand. Flights are expensive and sparse. Air Canada and Westjet have a few daily flights heading to Whitehorse from Vancouver. Air North has scheduled scheduled flights from Edmonton and Calgary. And that's it. Coming from New York, it took Rani a whole day to finally get to Whitehorse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for rental cars, there are a couple of Budgets and Driving Force in town. You may want to book early. By the beginning of August, neither company showed any stock left online. Our rental car from Driving Force costed $600 for a week, and we only drove it for like 6 hours. Quite expensive but there is no other way to get to trailhead other than hitchhiking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Permits are issued in the visitor center at Haines Junction, 2 hours west of Whitehorse. From Haines Junction, drive north west for another hour, and right after crossing Duke river, there's an old mining road parallel to the river. This is where the route starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at the trailhead at around 2:30 pm. First few miles was an easy walk on the old mining road. After Copper Creek, the road would continue to descend north. At that point, get off the road and head south west, circling the Atmosphere Mountain. Terrain was mostly tundra, but fortunately there weren't many bushes. We hiked a couple  more hours and called it the day at around 9pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06520.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a couple of hours' hike on tundra, we arrived at the valley leading to Hoge Pass. There's a warden's cabin half way into the valley. It sat at the boundary of the national park. Follow the creek upstream for another hour, we arrived at Hoge Pass at around 2pm. There was a vague trail that leaded to the pass. It was impossible to descend directly down the first valley. Instead hike up to the right side of the ridge and follow the other valley. The valley was steep and narrow. There were cliffs on both side. The surface was mostly rock and could be quite slippery. I do not recommend doing the pass on a wet day. We spent 5 hours scrambling down the valley and finally got out of it at 7pm. We were really exhausted and set camp at first sight of a flat area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06539.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rest of the way to Donjek river was quite easy. The route would then follow the river upstream. The hike was easy at first. It may be necessary to cross a couple of braids. After a few miles there would be places where the river ran right next to the cliff. We had to turn around and climb up the bank. There was heavy vegetation on the hill, including trees, bushes and tundra. We were fortunate that we stumbled upon a horse trail, so it wasn't so bad at the beginning. However we lost the trail after crossing one of the creeks and the second half of bushwhacking was pretty tough. We were also unwisely wearing short sleeves, so that left scratches on our arms. Even though it might be tempting to drop back down to the river, there were multiple occasions where it was cliff on the left side and uncrossable river in front. I would recommend staying up on the hill. We finally got to the front of the glacier at around 9pm and called it the day.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06571.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://talkingtrails.blogspot.com/2015/08/kluanes-wild-donjek-route.html&quot;&gt;Talking Trails blog&lt;/a&gt;, Bighorn Creek is not easy to cross and neither of us were that comfortable crossing creeks. We therefore elected to go with the alternative route over Expectation Pass. View on the pass was a highlight of the trip. There were also a half dozen of Dal sheep on the pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the pass at the first valley, the track we had on our map called for us to keep walking on the hillside, but the slope was pretty steep. We did not feel comfortable following it and had to follow the valley down until it intersected with Bighorn Creek again. The descend was not easy but there were vegetation, so we managed to fight our way down. Getting back to the original route, we hiked a couple of miles more until we encountered a cliff again. We retracted a little bit, climbed a more gentle slope and pitched our tent on a tiny area that was relatively flat at 10:30pm.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06617.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It started raining when we broke camp at 10am. We were warned by the ranger not to attempt the pass if weather was bad. &quot;You could die&quot; is what she said. With our experience on Hoge Pass, we were inclined to believe her. Not wanting to die, we walked half a mile, found a better campsite, lie in tent and rested for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were quite worried that if weather didn't get better, we would be trapped. I recalled that the Delorme Inreach I carried could actually receive weather forecast, so I gave it a try. Forecast for the next day was sunny until 5pm. We were slightly relieved but still skeptical about its accuracy. We decided to get up as early as possible to make sure we could climb down the pass before the rain came in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up at 5am and it was freezing, We took off at 7am and arrived on top of the pass an hour later. The climb was not hard. Going down, we were careful following the track on the map and descended from the second valley on the left. The valley was actually much easier than Hoge Pass. It was quite wide and slopes weren't that steep. We arrived at the bottom a couple of hours later around noon.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06668.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the trip reports we read, crossing Duke River looked scary. Plus hiking out of Copper Joe Creek as in the original route would cause some logistical inconvenience, as we would need to hitchhike back to where we parked the car. So we decided to follow scottw86's route and followed Duke River downstream. It was easy at the beginning, but about halfway down when we thought we would be able to hike all the way out this very day, the river met the cliffs again. We had to climb up the hill and bushwhack. While I still hoped to drop back down to Duke River, Rani decided (wisely) that we should head north to hit the old mining road we came in on. So we continued marching in thick vegetation and crossed multiple valleys along the way. We reached Granite Creek at around 6:30pm. We had been walking for over 13 hours and exhausted. Knowing that it wouldn't be possible to get out that day, we found a tiny spot on the river bed to set up our tents.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471812095014.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Day 7&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We crossed Granite Creek in the morning, and continued on. After 6 hours of relentless bushwhacking, we reached the mining road at 2:30m. It was a great relief. From there it took us another hour to get to our car, and we then drove all the way back to Whitehorse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06515.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06515&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06515.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06515&quot; title=&quot;DSC06515&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06520.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06520&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06520.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06520&quot; title=&quot;DSC06520&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06527.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06527&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06527.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06527&quot; title=&quot;DSC06527&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06533.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06533&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06533.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06533&quot; title=&quot;DSC06533&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06534.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06534&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06534.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06534&quot; title=&quot;DSC06534&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06535.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06535&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06535.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06535&quot; title=&quot;DSC06535&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06539.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06539&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06539.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06539&quot; title=&quot;DSC06539&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06540.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06540&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06540.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06540&quot; title=&quot;DSC06540&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06542.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06542&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06542.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06542&quot; title=&quot;DSC06542&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06546.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06546&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06546.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06546&quot; title=&quot;DSC06546&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06552.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06552&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06552.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06552&quot; title=&quot;DSC06552&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06559.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06559&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06559.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06559&quot; title=&quot;DSC06559&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06565.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06565&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06565.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06565&quot; title=&quot;DSC06565&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06571.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06571&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06571.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06571&quot; title=&quot;DSC06571&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06576.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06576&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06576.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06576&quot; title=&quot;DSC06576&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06583.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06583&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06583.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06583&quot; title=&quot;DSC06583&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06597.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06597&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06597.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06597&quot; title=&quot;DSC06597&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06599.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06599&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06599.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06599&quot; title=&quot;DSC06599&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06617.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06617&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06617.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06617&quot; title=&quot;DSC06617&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06621.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06621&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06621.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06621&quot; title=&quot;DSC06621&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06627.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06627&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06627.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06627&quot; title=&quot;DSC06627&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06631.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06631&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06631.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06631&quot; title=&quot;DSC06631&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06633.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06633&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06633.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06633&quot; title=&quot;DSC06633&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06637.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06637&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06637.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06637&quot; title=&quot;DSC06637&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06640.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06640&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06640.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06640&quot; title=&quot;DSC06640&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06648.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06648&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06648.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06648&quot; title=&quot;DSC06648&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06651.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06651&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06651.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06651&quot; title=&quot;DSC06651&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06658.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06658&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06658.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06658&quot; title=&quot;DSC06658&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06662.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06662&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06662.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06662&quot; title=&quot;DSC06662&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06668.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06668&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06668.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06668&quot; title=&quot;DSC06668&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06678.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06678&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06678.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06678&quot; title=&quot;DSC06678&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/DSC06679.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06679&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/DSC06679.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06679&quot; title=&quot;DSC06679&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788811962.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788811962&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788811962.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1471788811962&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788811962&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788856684.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788856684&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788856684.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1471788856684&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788856684&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788860979.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788860979&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788860979.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1471788860979&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788860979&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788892083.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788892083&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788892083.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1471788892083&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788892083&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788900621.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788900621&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471788900621.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1471788900621&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471788900621&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471812095014.jpg&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471812095014&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/donjek/mmexport1471812095014.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;mmexport1471812095014&quot; title=&quot;mmexport1471812095014&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">Donjek Route is a 60 mile backcountry route in Kluane National Park, Yukon Territory. My friend Rani and I did the route from Aug. 13th to Aug. 19th in 2016.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">John Muir Trail: Part 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="John Muir Trail: Part 3" /><published>2015-07-10T19:43:45-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-10T19:43:45-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part3.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the third part of the write-up for my JMT trip in June 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Red's Meadow to Tuolomne Meadow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right next to Red's Meadow, Devil's Postpile draws thousands of visitors  every year. But soon after I got back on trail, everything quieted down again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06401.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Devil's Postpile&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I settled down at Thousand Island Lake on Jun. 17th. Albeit beautiful, the section between Garnet Lake and Donohue Pass was heavily infested by mosquitoes. In fact, situation was so bad that mosquitoes looked more like smoke until you got closer. Headnet is strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day, I crossed the 11,000 feet Donohue Pass at around noon, officially entering Yosemite National Park. After the pass, it was an endless descent into Upper Lyell Canyon. The SOBO hikers I met didn't look thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06464.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Tuolomne Meadow to Happy Isle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 5pm, I arrived at Tuolomne Meadows. I got confused again when the GPS path suggested me continue on a ramp leading to Tioga Road (Bring a map folks!). There were shuttle buses standing by, running along Tioga Road. So I hopped on the bus, and was dropped off at Tenaya Lake. Camping is not allowed within a mile of Tioga Road, regardless of the kind of permit you hold. So I had to hike further south into the park, looking for a lake the bus driver told me about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06469.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This was not a very smart move. It was getting dark and I didn't have any idea how far I needed to walk. All I had was a TOPO map from the tiny screen of my GPS device. The trail was all uphill and mosquitoes were everywhere. I also ran out of water at Tuolomne, so there was quite some urgency. Two hours later just before dark I got to the unnamed lake. Surprisingly it was quite decent, much better than I had expected. By taking this route, I bypassed Cathedral Pass and shaved a day's hike off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06476.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Jun. 19th was my last day on JMT. I could barely contain the anxiety. I was expecting an easy hike, but there's still quite some ups and downs until Half Dome. A hike up Half Dome requires an additional permit. From what I heard, rangers were present checking the permits, so a sneak-up was out of the question. Afterwards trail passed by Nevada Fall and the last couple of miles of JMT was a steep switchback dropping 2000 feet in elevation. Eventually after much struggle, I got to the bottom of it, the official trailhead of JMT - Happy Isles. And it marked the end of this two-week hike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06507.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Happy Isles, there's a scheduled shuttle bus that takes you to the visitor center. From there &lt;a href=&quot;http://yarts.com/routes-and-schedules/merced-hwy-140/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;YART&lt;/a&gt; bus run a couple of times per day to Merced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_003.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;YART bus&lt;/span&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Merced&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps I was in the wrong neighborhood, but the shabby buildings and strip malls on 16th Street reminded me of the good old PG county. Hotel room was dead cheap though, so all was good. The next morning I boarded Amtrak and left for San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_001.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Merced&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06399.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06399&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06399.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06399&quot; title=&quot;DSC06399&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06401.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06401&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06401.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06401&quot; title=&quot;DSC06401&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06407.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06407&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06407.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06407&quot; title=&quot;DSC06407&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06417.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06417&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06417.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06417&quot; title=&quot;DSC06417&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06433.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06433&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06433.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06433&quot; title=&quot;DSC06433&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06440.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06440&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06440.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06440&quot; title=&quot;DSC06440&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06449.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06449&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06449.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06449&quot; title=&quot;DSC06449&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06450.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06450&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06450.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06450&quot; title=&quot;DSC06450&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06453.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06453&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06453.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06453&quot; title=&quot;DSC06453&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06456.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06456&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06456.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06456&quot; title=&quot;DSC06456&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06460.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06460&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06460.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06460&quot; title=&quot;DSC06460&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06461.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06461&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06461.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06461&quot; title=&quot;DSC06461&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06464.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06464&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06464.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06464&quot; title=&quot;DSC06464&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06469.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06469&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06469.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06469&quot; title=&quot;DSC06469&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06476.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06476&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06476.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06476&quot; title=&quot;DSC06476&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06482.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06482&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06482.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06482&quot; title=&quot;DSC06482&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06496.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06496&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06496.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06496&quot; title=&quot;DSC06496&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06507.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06507&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/DSC06507.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06507&quot; title=&quot;DSC06507&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150619_007.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150619_007&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150619_007.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150619_007&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150619_007&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_001.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150620_001&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_001.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150620_001&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150620_001&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_002.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150620_002&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_002.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150620_002&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150620_002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_003.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150620_003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part3/WP_20150620_003.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150620_003&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150620_003&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">This is the third part of the write-up for my JMT trip in June 2015.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">John Muir Trail: Part 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="John Muir Trail: Part 2" /><published>2015-07-09T18:01:59-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-09T18:01:59-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part2.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the second part of the write-up for my JMT trip in June 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Road's End to Kings River via Sierra High Route&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;From Road's End, Sierra High Route followed Copper Creek trail and winded up for 6000 feet. This was a gruesome climb that took me more than 4 hours to finally reach the end of the trail. The high route then went off-trail. I hiked over the Grouse Lake Pass and called it the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06067.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Next day (Jun. 10th) I woke up full of energy, couldn't wait to start the hike. But I soon learned the challenges. While navigation was not so hard, route finding was tricky, especially in early June. North faces of the passes were always covered with snow. Occasionally there were a few ambiguous sets of footprints, but most of time I needed to figure out the descending route myself. As a result, I walked much slower than I expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06129.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weather was also less than ideal. There was fog in the afternoon of the second day, so thick that the only way to navigate was by GPS. It was then followed by a chilly shower. After a miserable day, I set up camp at around 6pm before White pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06103.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last straw was the mosquitoes. Right after I struggled down the snowy north side of the Red Pass on Jun 11th, I dropped below tree line and reached the Marion Lake. Pretty as it was, this place was infested with hundreds of mosquitoes. Mid-June was right about the time the eggs hatched. Every time I passed by a bush, hundreds of them would rise like smoke and start to chase me desperately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took out my GPS and started blindly following its route, just so I could get out of there as soon as I can. It was not a wise decision. For some reason, the GPS file I got from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onthetrail.org/shr.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OntheTrail.com&lt;/a&gt; turned south to connect with the old Muir Trail, instead of heading north to the Frozen Lake Pass. By the time I realized, I was at the bottom of Cartridge Pass. To continue with this route meant a significant detour. The old Muir Trail was not maintained and few people actually hike this route. As a result, instead of a trail, all I saw was a 200 feet cliff covered by snow. To retrace my steps would mean to cross the mosquito zone again. It was also indicated in Roper's book that Frozen Lake Pass was quite difficult.  In the end I decided better the devil you know. Cartridge Pass was steep for the first two-thirds of the ascent. I had to hop over boulders to climb up. Combined with some crawling in the snow, I managed to get to the top. Hats off to two other hikers before me. Judging from their footprints they went straight-up from the snow field. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06162.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Kings River to Red's Meadow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Cartridge Pass there was a significant drop in elevation with a steep switchback towards Kings River. Initially the trail was not easy to recognize, but just follow the river and you would eventually reach the trail junction. After the junction, the route rejoined JMT. Having followed the High Route for three days, I decided to bail and hike JMT instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked faster once I got back on a maintained trail. Short with food, I had to walk 11-12 hours every day. As a result, I got blisters at Le Conte Canyon before Muir Pass, and developed left shin splint near Muir Trail Ranch. Mosquito situation was also getting worse. I had to take fewer rest stops, and taking a leak was a PITA. Moral was quite low at that time. I was contemplating to bail as soon as I reach Red's Meadow. Nonetheless, the scenery was hands-down magnificent. The trail leading to Muir Pass was the best I have ever hiked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06284.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately weather was getting better as I headed north. There was rain, fog or hail every day I spent in King's Canyon National Park. Once I crossed the boundary to John Muir Wilderness however, I hardly saw a drop of water again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06189.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last couple of days I had to ration the food. Those calculations were not pleasant. It turned out that I had just enough for me to get to Red's. My last dinner on Jun. 15th was some cereals. Breakfast the next day was a chocolate bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Mammoth Lake&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning of Jun. 16th, one week after I took off from Road's End, I arrived at Red's Meadow. From Red's Meadow there's bus service to Mammoth Lake every hour. Mammoth is ski town in winter. In summer the tracks become mountain bike trails. It has all the amenities I could ask for after 10 days in the wilderness. Trip to MacDonald had never been so pleasant. In less than 24 hours, I ingested 5000 calories. Fully refreshed, I tossed the idea of bailing and decided to continue the hike to Yosemite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06393.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06026.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06026&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06026.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06026&quot; title=&quot;DSC06026&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06038.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06038&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06038.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06038&quot; title=&quot;DSC06038&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06048.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06048&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06048.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06048&quot; title=&quot;DSC06048&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06061.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06061&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06061.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06061&quot; title=&quot;DSC06061&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06067.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06067&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06067.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06067&quot; title=&quot;DSC06067&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06080.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06080&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06080.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06080&quot; title=&quot;DSC06080&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06081.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06081&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06081.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06081&quot; title=&quot;DSC06081&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06084.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06084&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06084.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06084&quot; title=&quot;DSC06084&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06094.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06094&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06094.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06094&quot; title=&quot;DSC06094&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06095.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06095&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06095.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06095&quot; title=&quot;DSC06095&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06096.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06096&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06096.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06096&quot; title=&quot;DSC06096&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06097.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06097&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06097.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06097&quot; title=&quot;DSC06097&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06103.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06103&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06103.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06103&quot; title=&quot;DSC06103&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06104.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06104&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06104.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06104&quot; title=&quot;DSC06104&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06107.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06107&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06107.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06107&quot; title=&quot;DSC06107&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06108.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06108&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06108.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06108&quot; title=&quot;DSC06108&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06116.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06116&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06116.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06116&quot; title=&quot;DSC06116&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06117.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06117&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06117.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06117&quot; title=&quot;DSC06117&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06120.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06120&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06120.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06120&quot; title=&quot;DSC06120&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06123.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06123&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06123.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06123&quot; title=&quot;DSC06123&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06129.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06129&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06129.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06129&quot; title=&quot;DSC06129&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06131.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06131&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06131.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06131&quot; title=&quot;DSC06131&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06134.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06134&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06134.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06134&quot; title=&quot;DSC06134&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06147.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06147&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06147.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06147&quot; title=&quot;DSC06147&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06150.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06150&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06150.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06150&quot; title=&quot;DSC06150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06153.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06153&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06153.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06153&quot; title=&quot;DSC06153&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06154.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06154&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06154.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06154&quot; title=&quot;DSC06154&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06156.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06156&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06156.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06156&quot; title=&quot;DSC06156&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06159.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06159&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06159.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06159&quot; title=&quot;DSC06159&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06160.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06160&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06160.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06160&quot; title=&quot;DSC06160&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06162.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06162&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06162.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06162&quot; title=&quot;DSC06162&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06163.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06163&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06163.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06163&quot; title=&quot;DSC06163&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06164.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06164&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06164.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06164&quot; title=&quot;DSC06164&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06169.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06169&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06169.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06169&quot; title=&quot;DSC06169&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06170.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06170&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06170.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06170&quot; title=&quot;DSC06170&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06176.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06176&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06176.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06176&quot; title=&quot;DSC06176&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06188.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06188&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06188.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06188&quot; title=&quot;DSC06188&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06189.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06189&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06189.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06189&quot; title=&quot;DSC06189&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06193.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06193&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06193.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06193&quot; title=&quot;DSC06193&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06195.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06195&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06195.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06195&quot; title=&quot;DSC06195&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06196.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06196&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06196.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06196&quot; title=&quot;DSC06196&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06211.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06211&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06211.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06211&quot; title=&quot;DSC06211&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06224.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06224&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06224.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06224&quot; title=&quot;DSC06224&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06239.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06239&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06239.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06239&quot; title=&quot;DSC06239&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06243.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06243&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06243.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06243&quot; title=&quot;DSC06243&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06251.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06251&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06251.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06251&quot; title=&quot;DSC06251&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06252.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06252&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06252.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06252&quot; title=&quot;DSC06252&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06255.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06255&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06255.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06255&quot; title=&quot;DSC06255&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06258.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06258&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06258.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06258&quot; title=&quot;DSC06258&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06262.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06262&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06262.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06262&quot; title=&quot;DSC06262&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06264.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06264&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06264.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06264&quot; title=&quot;DSC06264&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06284.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06284&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06284.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06284&quot; title=&quot;DSC06284&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06288.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06288&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06288.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06288&quot; title=&quot;DSC06288&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06292.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06292&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06292.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06292&quot; title=&quot;DSC06292&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06310.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06310&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06310.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06310&quot; title=&quot;DSC06310&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06319.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06319&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06319.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06319&quot; title=&quot;DSC06319&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06324.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06324&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06324.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06324&quot; title=&quot;DSC06324&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06326.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06326&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06326.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06326&quot; title=&quot;DSC06326&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06328.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06328&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06328.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06328&quot; title=&quot;DSC06328&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06335.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06335&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06335.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06335&quot; title=&quot;DSC06335&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06339.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06339&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06339.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06339&quot; title=&quot;DSC06339&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06342.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06342&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06342.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06342&quot; title=&quot;DSC06342&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06351.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06351&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06351.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06351&quot; title=&quot;DSC06351&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06352.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06352&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06352.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06352&quot; title=&quot;DSC06352&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06358.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06358&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06358.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06358&quot; title=&quot;DSC06358&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06360.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06360&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06360.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06360&quot; title=&quot;DSC06360&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06365.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06365&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06365.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06365&quot; title=&quot;DSC06365&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06375.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06375&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06375.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06375&quot; title=&quot;DSC06375&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06382.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06382&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06382.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06382&quot; title=&quot;DSC06382&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06390.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06390&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06390.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06390&quot; title=&quot;DSC06390&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06392.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06392&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06392.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06392&quot; title=&quot;DSC06392&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06393.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06393&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/DSC06393.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06393&quot; title=&quot;DSC06393&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150616_006.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150616_006&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150616_006.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150616_006&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150616_006&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150617_005.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150617_005&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150617_005.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150617_005&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150617_005&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150617_006.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150617_006&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150617_006.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150617_006&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150617_006&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150617_010.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150617_010&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part2/WP_20150617_010.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150617_010&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150617_010&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">This is the second part of the write-up for my JMT trip in June 2015.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">John Muir Trail: Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="John Muir Trail: Part 1" /><published>2015-07-08T14:52:27-07:00</published><updated>2015-07-08T14:52:27-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/07/jmt-part1.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;John Muir Trail is a 211 mile trail between Yosemite and Mt Whitney. It is widely regarded as one of the best trails in the world. I hiked (most of) the trail northbound from Jun. 6th to Jun. 19th, with some detour on Sierra High Route from Road's End to Mather Pass.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I flew into Reno on Jun. 4th. The next day I took &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.estransit.com/routes-schedule/395-routes/lone-pine-to-reno/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Route 395 bus&lt;/a&gt; operated by Eastern Sierra Transit to Lone Pine. On Jun. 6th I went to the ranger station for a wilderness permit. At 8 am in the morning, there were about 10 groups waiting outside. The ranger held a quick lottery draw when he showed up. It was more like a formality, as all of us got our permits with no problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/WP_20150605_011.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went back to town, checked out from the hotel and walked to the intersection to Whitney Portal to hitch a ride. There are quite a few people heading to the portal every day. It took me only 5 minutes to get a ride, one of the smoothest hitchhiking experiences I ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05746.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Mt. Whitney&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started at Whitney Portal, about 8000 feet above sea level. Early June would be considered too early to attempt the peak without mountaineering gears, but thanks to the record low snow year, the hike was totally doable with just trail runners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything went very smoothly in the first few hours. Weather was good, even though I could see the clouds closing in. I was carrying a fairly heavy bag with 5 days of food, but it was first day, so with fresh legs and adrenaline, I was walking at a good pace. I arrived at Trail Camp around 1 pm, and decided to push it despite the clouds. I had some unfinished schoolwork and probably shouldn't do this trip to begin with, so I wanted to finish the hike sooner rather than later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05823.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after Trail Camp was the infamous &quot;99 switchbacks&quot;. There were still quite a few patches of snow at the cables, so I put on my microspikes. I didn't think it was really necessary. This was also the only time I used them during the trip. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05824.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weather continued to deteriorate and it started hailing when I got closer to Trail Crest. I was wearing short sleeve T-shirt before Trail Camp and felt quite warm. By the time I got to Trail Crest, I was wearing a long-sleeve base layer and a wind shirt, and was still freezing and worried about hypothermia. I probably should just descent to Guitar Lake, but my ego got the better of me. I put my backpack down and marched towards the summit. Half way up, it started snowing. Soon it turned to a blizzard. By the time I arrived at the top, I couldn't see a thing. I snatched a few pictures and rushed down. I almost lost the trail because of the poor visibility. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05851.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me 2 hours to get down to Guitar Lake. I was really exhausted after the long day, and passed out in my tent after a quick dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05875.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Forester Pass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second day was a low mileage day. I had a headache the previous night, and thought it was a symptom of altitude sickness. Turned out it was just dehydration. I drank some water, had a good sleep and woke up at 8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trail was fairly easy for this section, mostly flat. I arrived at camp around 3 in the afternoon. Having just experienced a full-scale whiteout at Whitney, I decided to call it a day and leave the pass for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05913.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Jun. 8th, I got up slightly earlier at 7 am, but still one of the last. The PCT hikers were long gone by the time I stepped out of the tent. At over 13,000 feet above sea level, Forester Pass is the highest point on JMT. It was relatively easy from south, but still it involved a long and steep 2 hour climb. The view at the top was magnificent. It was one of the highlights of this trip.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05970.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;North face of the pass still had quite a bit of snow. But there were already a few paths left by earlier JMT and PCT hikers, so crossing those snow fields wasn't a big issue.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05977.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Road's End/ Cedar Grove&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was all downhill from Forester pass. Last campsite is about 4 miles before Road's End. As it was getting late, I settled down at the site, and met a few hikers doing the Rae Lakes Loop. Really friendly folks. They gave me some of their food. The next day I hiked a couple miles of switchbacks and reached Road's End at 9 am. Nearest resupply point Cedar Grove is another 5 miles away on paved road. Hitchhiking shouldn't be difficult. Unfortunately I was out in the morning, and there was little traffic going out. So I ended up walking more than half the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's a lodge at Cedar Grove, as well as a small restaurant and general store. It would be a nice place for a rest day but I was in a hurry. So I bought some trail mix and snicker bars, and hitched a ride back to Road's End.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06025.jpg&quot; width =90%&gt;


&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05746.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05746&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05746.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05746&quot; title=&quot;DSC05746&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05763.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05763&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05763.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05763&quot; title=&quot;DSC05763&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05817.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05817&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05817.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05817&quot; title=&quot;DSC05817&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05823.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05823&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05823.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05823&quot; title=&quot;DSC05823&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05824.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05824&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05824.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05824&quot; title=&quot;DSC05824&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05829.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05829&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05829.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05829&quot; title=&quot;DSC05829&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05838.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05838&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05838.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05838&quot; title=&quot;DSC05838&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05839.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05839&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05839.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05839&quot; title=&quot;DSC05839&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05851.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05851&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05851.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05851&quot; title=&quot;DSC05851&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05855.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05855&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05855.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05855&quot; title=&quot;DSC05855&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05857.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05857&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05857.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05857&quot; title=&quot;DSC05857&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05875.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05875&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05875.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05875&quot; title=&quot;DSC05875&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05900.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05900&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05900.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05900&quot; title=&quot;DSC05900&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05913.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05913&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05913.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05913&quot; title=&quot;DSC05913&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05945.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05945&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05945.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05945&quot; title=&quot;DSC05945&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05952.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05952&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05952.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05952&quot; title=&quot;DSC05952&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05954.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05954&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05954.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05954&quot; title=&quot;DSC05954&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05960.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05960&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05960.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05960&quot; title=&quot;DSC05960&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05970.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05970&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05970.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05970&quot; title=&quot;DSC05970&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05977.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05977&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05977.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05977&quot; title=&quot;DSC05977&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05978.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05978&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05978.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05978&quot; title=&quot;DSC05978&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05981.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05981&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC05981.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05981&quot; title=&quot;DSC05981&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06005.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06005&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06005.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06005&quot; title=&quot;DSC06005&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06015.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06015&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06015.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06015&quot; title=&quot;DSC06015&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06021.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06021&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06021.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06021&quot; title=&quot;DSC06021&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06022.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06022&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06022.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06022&quot; title=&quot;DSC06022&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06025.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC06025&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/DSC06025.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC06025&quot; title=&quot;DSC06025&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/jmt-part1/WP_20150605_011.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150605_011&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/jmt-part1/WP_20150605_011.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150605_011&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150605_011&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">John Muir Trail is a 211 mile trail between Yosemite and Mt Whitney. It is widely regarded as one of the best trails in the world. I hiked (most of) the trail northbound from Jun. 6th to Jun. 19th, with some detour on Sierra High Route from Road's End to Mather Pass.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Poor Man’s Machu Picchu</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2015/01/machu-picchu.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Poor Man's Machu Picchu" /><published>2015-01-15T16:09:04-08:00</published><updated>2015-01-15T16:09:04-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2015/01/machu-picchu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2015/01/machu-picchu.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Machu Picchu is Peru's most famous landmark. I visited the site on Jan. 3rd, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Lima to Cusco&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though this short one hour flight from Lima cost 200USD, most tourists still choose the plane option. For a good  reason. Cusco is located on the other side of Andes. Bus ride from Lima took 20 hours. However as a frugal traveler, I went with the bus without much hesitation. I was coming from Huaraz back to Lima on Dec. 30th. By the time I got to La Norte Plaza at Lima, the only available seat was a CIVA cama económico at the very last row next to the restroom. On a tight schedule, I took that seat as I didn't want to waste another day at Lima. It was not a pleasant trip. I sat next to a mother with her child on her lap. And the baby kept spitting. The tiny TV in the bus kept showing the Expendables in Spanish over and over. I didn't bring enough water and was dehydrated. At the end of Dec. 31st, when we finally arrived at Cusco, I got really sick and had to ditch my initial plan to hike the Salcantay Route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, view on this cross Andes road trip was not bad at all. My return trip was on Cruz del Sur and it was a very enjoyable ride. I think whatever company, as long as it's not económico, it should be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150105_003.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Cusco&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Most tourists would stay at San Blas neighborhood, and limit their activities around Plaza de Armas. It's after all where most of the tourist attractions are located. I don't think the city lives up to the hype. A day tour is enough. Most Inca architectures have been destroyed by the Spanish centuries ago. Even Qoricancha was basically a Christian church with some Inca ruins in it. Meh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150101_036.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Plaza de Armas&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Cusco to Machu Picchu Pueblo&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are numerous articles on the internet detailing the route (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;http://theinternationalrambler.blogspot.ca/2011/05/machu-picchu-or-bust.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;the International Rambler&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Cusco take the combi and get off at Santa Maria. From Santa Maria there should be a few collectivos waiting right on the other side of the street that would take you to Santa Teresa. At Santa Teresa transfer again to the hydroelectrico, the end of the road and the starting point of a 10 km trek to Machupicchu Pueblo following the train track. Sometimes it's also possible to get directly from Santa Maria to hydroecletrico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150104_002.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption text-muted&quot;&gt;Santa Maria&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might not be a well-known approach 5 years ago, but by the time I was there in 2015, it got so popular that there were hundreds of people walking on the track. In fact, there was even a market at a hydroeclectrico, and a few hostels alongside the track. Trains occasionally pass by, but at a fairly slow speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class = 'embed-container'&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/123126311&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Machupicchu Pueblo&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Machupicchu Pueblo used be called Aguas Calientes, but the name was officially changed recently. After all, Machu Picchu is why anyone would go through all the trouble to visit. It's not surprising at all that everything was overpriced in this chaotic, tourist-infested town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_053.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machu Picchu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Machupicchu Pueblo, you can either walk or take a bus to get to machu Picchu. I took the bus, but the walk which follows a steep switchback, is definitely doable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_003.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ticket was about 150 sols for foreigners. Students get half price. I was told that it didn't have to be an international student card, a regular one issued by the university was enough. I wish I had known that beforehand. Tickets can be booked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.machupicchu.gob.pe/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;online&lt;/a&gt;, and I strongly recommend booking in advance, especially if you want to visit Huayna Picchu ( the mountain at the back). There's a quota for the number of visitors every day, and they fill out fast. I wasn't able to get the Huayna Picchu permit, but did snatch a pass to Machu Picchu Montaña (the mountain at the front).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's not much to talk about the visit itself. January is right in the middle of a monsoon season, so it I encountered a few downpours. And it did get chilly with the rain. So I suggest taking a rain coat with you if you are visiting during the wet season. Other than that, it took some time to get to the top of the the montaña, but the view was cool.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;img class=&quot;mx-auto d-block&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_051.jpg&quot; width = 90%&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I retraced the route and went back to Santa Maria the same day. I arrived at hydroecletrico at around 5pm. There was only one combi still waiting there. I would recommend getting there earlier. There's nothing at hydroecletrico. You don't want to get stranded there. There's not a lot of lodging options at Santa Teresa, and at 7pm they were all full. So I had to take another combi to Santa Maria. After I finally settled down, I played some volleyball (!) with locals and some Brazilian tourists. The game was fun and locals played really well. There's one Brazilian though, who kept rushing to the front row and hit balls that were not set to him. It drove me nuts.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, Machu Picchu trip is more of a &quot;been there, done that&quot; kind of experience. Getting there is a PITA. The ticket is expensive, and everything in Cusco and Machupicchu Pueblo is overpriced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
    .image-gallery {overflow: auto; margin-left: -1%!important;}
    .image-gallery a {float: left; display: block; margin: 0 0 1% 1%; width: 19%; text-align: center; text-decoration: none!important;}
    .image-gallery a span {display: block; text-overflow: ellipsis; overflow: hidden; white-space: nowrap; padding: 3px 0;}
    .image-gallery a img {width: 100%; display: block;}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-gallery&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/10427684_10155024873770554_5590150767682682214_n.jpg&quot; title=&quot;10427684_10155024873770554_5590150767682682214_n&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/10427684_10155024873770554_5590150767682682214_n.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;10427684_10155024873770554_5590150767682682214_n&quot; title=&quot;10427684_10155024873770554_5590150767682682214_n&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05612.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05612&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05612.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05612&quot; title=&quot;DSC05612&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05613.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05613&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05613.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05613&quot; title=&quot;DSC05613&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05635.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05635&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05635.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05635&quot; title=&quot;DSC05635&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05646.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05646&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05646.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05646&quot; title=&quot;DSC05646&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05656.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05656&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05656.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05656&quot; title=&quot;DSC05656&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05698.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05698&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05698.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05698&quot; title=&quot;DSC05698&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05720.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05720&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05720.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05720&quot; title=&quot;DSC05720&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05733.jpg&quot; title=&quot;DSC05733&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/DSC05733.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;DSC05733&quot; title=&quot;DSC05733&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150101_029.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150101_029&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150101_029.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150101_029&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150101_029&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150101_036.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150101_036&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150101_036.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150101_036&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150101_036&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_002.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_002&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_002.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150102_002&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_004.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_004&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_004.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150102_004&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_004&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_006.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_006&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_006.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150102_006&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_006&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_011.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_011&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150102_011.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150102_011&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150102_011&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_003.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_003.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_003&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_003&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_024.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_024&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_024.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_024&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_024&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_031.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_031&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_031.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_031&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_031&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_034.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_034&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_034.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_034&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_034&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_042.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_042&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_042.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_042&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_042&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_050.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_050&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_050.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_050&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_050&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_051.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_051&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_051.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_051&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_051&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_053.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_053&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_053.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_053&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_053&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_055.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_055&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150103_055.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150103_055&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150103_055&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150104_002.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150104_002&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150104_002.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150104_002&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150104_002&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150104_004.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150104_004&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150104_004.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150104_004&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150104_004&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150105_003.jpg&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150105_003&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//images.weserv.nl/?url=localhost:4000/img/posts/machu-picchu/WP_20150105_003.jpg&amp;w=250&amp;h=250&amp;output=jpg&amp;q=50&amp;t=square&quot; alt=&quot;WP_20150105_003&quot; title=&quot;WP_20150105_003&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Longyuan Du</name></author><summary type="html">Machu Picchu is Peru's most famous landmark. I visited the site on Jan. 3rd, 2015.</summary></entry></feed>